<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
USAGE/FOR DUMMIES <3
================================================
<event> -> Used to group related dialogs (will scope), so a dialog from
           EventA will not be able to refer to a dialog from EventB

           name: identifier of the event (will show up as title in game)
           type: defines what type of room the event will show up in
                 currently (event, entrance, exit, alter, item and shop)
           level: defines what floor type this event will should up (dungeon,
                  lava, hell, etc...) can use special word 'any' to allow in
                  any floor type

<tag> -> Used inside <event>. Will replace special identifiers in templates
         such as "[word]" where 'word' is the identifier to be replaced. Usage
         indentifier@replacement. Ex. object@sword with replace [object] with
         sword. Also useful in general to tag what the event is all about.

<dialog> ->
<choices>
<chance>
<condition>
<action>
-->
<data>

    <event name="the catacombs" type="entrance" level="catacomb">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>The Catacombs, once a place to rest the bodies of those who pasted on. Now a cesspool for necromancers, grave robbers and abominations alike. Hoards of undead and terrifying creatures await you at every turn. Trend carefully.</body>
        </dialog>
    </event>

    <event name="lost spirits" type="event" level="catacomb">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>You see wandering spirits ahead of your party. Shimmering in the distance you can hear them moaning and wailing.

            "I can't see the light"

            As they slowly drift aimlessly.</body>
            <choices>
                <choice name="leave"> - Leave them be</choice>
                <choice name="approach"> - Approach the lost spirits</choice>
            </choices>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="leave-fail">
            <body>Suddenly, the spirit notice you're presence. Their wails turn to screeches as they dash angrily towards your party!

            "Why won't anyone help us?!?"</body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="leave">
            <body>Your party decides to leave them be. As you and the spirits take separate path down the catacombs, you hear their moans grow increasingly distant.</body>
            <chance fail="leave-fail">50</chance>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="leave-fail">
            <body>Suddenly, the spirit notice you're presence. Their wails turn to screeches and dash angrily towards your party!

            "Why won't anyone help me?!?"</body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="approach">
            <body>Your party cautiously walks towards the spirits. They notice your presence and turn to confront you.

            "Help, can you please help us?"</body>
            <choices>
                <choice name="help"> - "How can we help you?"</choice>
                <choice name="abandon"> - "You're on your own."</choice>
            </choices>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="help">
            <body>"Please, the Necromancer has sealed these catacombs, none who are dead can escape it and find peace."
            </body>
            <choices>
                <choice name="promise"> - Promise to defeat the Necromancer
                </choice>
            </choices>
            <chance name="help-fail">80</chance>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="help-fail">
            <body>"No, no, you can't help us! Tricks, more tricks!"

                The spirits refuse your offer of help. They shriek curses at your party as they turn to fight you.
            </body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>

        <dialog name="abandon">
            <body>"Why, why won't you help us?"

                Their wails turn to screeches and dash angrily towards your party!</body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="promise">
            <body>The spirits are pleased by your promise of good will. They give your party shards to help you on your quest.
            </body>
            <action>loot shard:100</action>
        </dialog>
    </event>

    <event name="the occult" type="event" level="catacomb">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>Your path is blocked by cloaked figures up ahead. They confront you as you approach.

            "Have you come to worship the Master? Or are you another heretic that spurns the gift he offers freely?"

            The man who spoke reveals a chalice from his garb. He holds it up to you. A sweet aroma fills the room.

            "Drink the Master's gift and feel his embrace."
            </body>
            <choices>
                <choice name="drink"> - Drink from the cup</choice>
                <choice name="refuse"> - Refuse the drink</choice>
            </choices>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="drink">
            <body>The man grins as he hands your party the cup. Each member drinks deeply before returning the chalice to its owner.

            "Go forward now, and find the Master. He will endow you will his eternal blessing."

            They direct you forward, but as you walk, you find your vision blurred and your steps weakened. The drought has crippled your party for your next encounter.
            </body>
            <!-- <action>crippled</action> -->
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="refuse">
            <body>The man frowns and the cloaked figures encircle your party.

            "The Master doesn't offer his gift lightly. Death comes to us all, even to those who spurn it."

            The men draw their weapons and assault your party
            </body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
    </event>

    <event name="boatman" type="event" level="catacomb">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>As you continue your descent, you hear running water up ahead. A thin man stands next a boat on the shore of a short river that runs through the underground.

            "Are you here for the ferry travelers? I can help you cross for a fee of shards."
            </body>
            <choices>
                <choice name="ferry"> - Pay the boatman 100 shards to cross</choice>
                <choice name="continue"> - Ignore the boatman</choice>
            </choices>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="ferry">
            <body>Your party boards the vessel and the ferryman pushes off from the shore.

            Upon arriving at the other side, your party encounters a dark chamber hidden from view on the other shore. They discover equipment and shards within. Your party searches through the treasures for valuables and continues.
            </body>
            <action>loot shard:100</action>
            <action>loot</action>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="continue">
            <body>You refuse the ferryman's offer and continue deeper into the catacombs.
            </body>
        </dialog>
    </event>

    <event name="grave robbers" type="event" level="catacomb">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>As you continue down your path, you hear hushed whispers up ahead.

            "Hey Jim, come over here! This one's got some good stuff!"

            Your party approaches stealthily and observes some men crouched over a tomb.

            "Look at all theses shards! Haha, we'll never need to worry about money again boys!"

            As you watch the men rummage through the grave, one of your party members stumbles on a nearby crack and lets out a startled exclamation

            "SHHH! Did you hear that?"
            </body>
            <choices>
                <choice name="confront"> - Confront the grave robbers</choice>
                <choice name="cat"> - Meow? </choice>
            </choices>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="confront">
            <body>Your party reveals themselves to the pillagers, weapons drawn.

            "Hrmph, always trouble down in the catacombs," growls their leader.

            "Guess we'll have to do this the hard way. Let's show 'em to the light boys!"
            </body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="cat-fail">
            <body>"We know you're out there!"

            The men draw their weapons and assault your party.
            </body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
        <dialog name="cat">
            <body>"It's nothing boss, just a cat."

            The men return to their focus to the tomb as your party sneaks past.
            </body>
            <chance name="cat-fail">20</chance>
        </dialog>
    </event>

<!--     <event name="the caves" type="entrance" level="cave">
    </event>
 -->

    <event name="Shop Found" type="shop" level="any">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>You spot a shop.</body>
            <action>shop</action>
        </dialog>
    </event>

    <event name="Ambush!" type="monster" level="any">
        <dialog name="main">
            <body>You're party is surrounded by monsters.</body>
            <action>battle</action>
        </dialog>
    </event>



</data>